<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Brandon Young&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Brandon Young&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Histograms</title>
      <link>/post/histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/histogram/</guid>
      <description>HistogramsOne other way to visually represent data is by inserting the data into a histogram chart. A histogram is a diagram consisting of rectangles whose area is proportional to the frequency of a variable and whose width is equal to the class interval.
First we will import the necessary packages:
library(Lahman)library(sqldf)## Loading required package: gsubfn## Loading required package: proto## Loading required package: RSQLitelibrary(ggplot2)Now we will use the following syntax to represent the data in a histogram chart:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatterplot</title>
      <link>/post/scatterplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scatterplot/</guid>
      <description>ScatterplotsAnother way to visually represent data is by using a scatterplot. A scatterplot is a type of plot or mathematical diagram using Cartesian coordinates to display values for typically two variables for a set of data.
First we will import the necessary packages:
library(Lahman)library(sqldf)## Loading required package: gsubfn## Loading required package: proto## Loading required package: RSQLitelibrary(devtools)library(ggplot2)Next we will extract the data:
query&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;SELECT playerID,sum(HR) AS career_HR,sum(SO) AS career_SO FROM Batting GROUP BY playerID HAVING sum(HR)&amp;gt;=400&amp;quot;result&amp;lt;-sqldf(query)And now we will visualize said data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series</title>
      <link>/post/timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/timeseries/</guid>
      <description>Time SeriesThe last way of visually representing data is through a time series plot. A time series plot displays values against time. They are similar to x-y graphs, but while an x-y graph can plot a variety of “x” variables (for example, height, weight, age), timeplots can only display time on the x-axis. Unlike pie charts and bar charts, these plots do not have categories. Timeplots are good for showing how data changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>barplot</title>
      <link>/post/barplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/barplot/</guid>
      <description>Bar PlotsData Visualization is an important concept in data science. Here we will be using a bar plot as an example of data visualization. A bar chart or bar graph is a chart or graph that presents categorical data with rectangular bars with heights or lengths proportional to the values that they represent.
First we will install the necessary packages for this example:
library(Lahman)library(sqldf)## Loading required package: gsubfn## Loading required package: proto## Loading required package: RSQLitelibrary(devtools)library(ggplot2)In this example we will be looking at all of the homerun totals of all of the teams in the MLB during the 1980’s:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>